Finding aid to the Linda Stout papers SSC.MS.00004
Sophia Smith Collection
Linda Stout papers
1987-2011
Sophia Smith Collection
Stout, Linda
SSC.MS.00004
3.75 linear feet (4 boxes.)
The collection contains the professional papers of Linda Stout, a peace activist in the latter part of the 20th century, including speeches, writings, and the records of the Piedmont Peace Project.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Accruals
This collection is comprised of the following accessions, some of which may not have accession records. Accession numbers: 03S-13, 04S-52, 13S-20. Accessions were received on the following dates: 2003-03-12, 2004-08-12, 2013-05-06.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection was donated to Smith College by Linda Stout in 2003, 2004, and 2013.
Related Materials
Voices of Feminism Oral History Project
Scope and Contents
Contains annotated typescripts of Stout's book, Bridging the Class Divide (1996); videotapes of Stout speaking in various venues in the late 1980s and 1990s; articles and clippings about Stout and her involvement with the Piedmont Peace Project; typescript of an oral history taken at the Bunting Institute (1993); and partial records of the Piedmont Peace Project.
Peace-- Societies, etc.--United States--History--Sources; Women and peace--History--20th century--Sources; Working class women--United States--Biography--Sources; Piedmont Peace Project (Kannapolis, N.C.); The Peace Development Fund; Spirit in Action (Belchertown, MA); Stout, Linda Kaye, 1954-; Manuscripts; Notes; Book; Typescripts; Videotapes; clippings; articles; Manuals; Lists; Oral histories; Stout, Linda; Stout, Linda
- Linda Stout papers and video recordings on "Bridging the Class Divide" and Piedmont Peace Project, 1987-1997; Accession 2003-S-0013; .75 linear feet
  General
  - Transcripts of two speeches, No date; Accession 2003-S-0013 (Box 1)
  - Book, "Bridging the Class Divide," by Linda Stout, 1996; 2003-S-0013 (Box 1)
  - Annotated drafts, notes, correspondence pertaining to "Bridging the Class Divide," by Linda Stout, 1994-1996; 2003-S-0013 (Box 1)
  - Transcript, Linda Stout oral history, Bunting Institute, 1993 May; 2003-S-0013 (Box 1)
  - Transcript, "Bridging the Class Divide,", 1996; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Bound photocopy, "Bridging the Class Divide.", No date; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Review, "Bridging the Class Divide.", 1997; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Media bibliography, "Bridging the Class Divide.", 1997; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Piedmont Peace Project literature, 1992; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Piedmont Peace Project, Five-Year Fundraising Marketing Plan, circa 1999; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Piedmont Peace Project media coverage bibliography, 1989-1993; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Piedmont Peace Project: media coverage of Proctor-Silex campaign, 1991; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Piedmont Peace Project press release, 1996; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Piedmont Peace Project: notes regarding harassment, 1977-1995; 20013-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Videotapes pertaining to Piedmont Peace Project, 1987-1994 and no date; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Videotape, Linda stout speaking at 2nd annual Massfreeze conference, 1987 November 15; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
    Speech entitled, "Classism and Grassroots Organizing."
  - Videotape: "Piedmont Peace Project Presents: Rev. Dr. Joseph E Lowery.", 1989 April 2; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Videotape: Linda stout, First Unitarian Church, Newton, MA, 1989 November 6; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Videotape: "Piedmont Peace Project: Introduction", 1991; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Videotape: WRAL report, Proctor-Silex plant closing, 1991 April 4; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Videotape: " Why Aren't We Winning?: Building Multi-racial Multi-class Organizations for Social Change", 1993 April 28; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Videotape: Linda Stout, colloquium speech, Bunting Institute, Cambridge, MA, 1993 November 8; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Videotape: "Piedmont Peace Project", No date; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Videotape: "Why Are We in the Middle East", No date; 2003-S-0013 (Box 2)
  - Segments of transcript, "Bridging the Class Divide", No date; 2003-S-0013 (Box 3)
- Angela Barth 2003 essay on Linda Stout and miscellaneous pamphlets, 2003 and no date; 2004-S-0052; 0.25 linear feet (1 box)
  Stout, Linda, 1954-
  - Pamphlet, "Sprit in Action: Transforming the Way We Do Change", No date; 2004-S-0052 (Box 1)
  - Pamphlet: "Circles of Change: Transforming the Way We Do Change", No date; 2004-S-005 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous materials related to Linda Stout, 1991-2011; 2013-S-0020; Stout, Linda; 1 linear feet (1 box)
  Stout, Linda
  - Articles related to Linda Stout, 1991-2011; 2013-S-0013 (Box 1)
  - Facilitator's manual: "Circles of Change", 2002; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum guide: "Spirit in Action, Facilitating Circles of Change", 2005; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)
  - Linda stout resume, 1995; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)
  - "Circles of Change: Transforming the Way We Do Change", circa 2004; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)
  - Progressive Communicators Network: "Raise Every Voice", 2007; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous brochures, handouts, reports, 2001-2007; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)
  - Ford grant materials, 2004; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)
  - VHS: two Linda Stout speeches, 1993; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)
  - 15 DVDs: Linda Stout speeches, workshops, 1991-2011; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)
  - CD: Studs Terkel interview with Linda Stout for "Bridging the Class Divide", 1997; 2013-S-0020 (Box 1)